<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learn Python by Practice on Practice Python</title>
    <link>https://practice-python.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learn Python by Practice on Practice Python</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 08:09:34 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://practice-python.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://practice-python.github.io/basics/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 15:21:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-python.github.io/basics/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with basic traditional program that will print &amp;ldquo;Hello, World!&amp;quot;.
See following code and Hit submit
 print(&#34;Hello, world!&#34;)  success_msg(&#34;Great job!&#34;)  Just hit submit button.   Explanation One the left hand side you see script.py and on the right hand side you see Ipython shell, its same as terminal, you can directly type command on it and hit enter to execute.
inside script.py, we used print() function (we will cover later) and we are passing &amp;ldquo;Hello World!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variables</title>
      <link>https://practice-python.github.io/basics/variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 20:19:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-python.github.io/basics/variables/</guid>
      <description>What is Variable ? You can think variable as drawers, like you have drawers to store clothes, files, books etc and you know which drawer has which things using the labels or tag.
So in programming, you store the data and you labeled it as the thing you refer. Variables are common for every programming/scripting language. Every script/program keep track of stuff, like when you create facebook login you have to feel details like name, age, sex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generators</title>
      <link>https://practice-python.github.io/advanced/generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 08:09:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-python.github.io/advanced/generators/</guid>
      <description>To understand generators you must know functions, iterable and yield so let&amp;rsquo;s understand that first
How does function works? When you call function it&amp;rsquo;s start from the first line until return statement or if there is any unexpected error occurred i.e. exeption
Function returns its result once and then its clears all function state to default, means you lost all intermediate variables etc after return.
What is iteration, iterable, and iterator?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Todo</title>
      <link>https://practice-python.github.io/basics/todo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 20:12:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-python.github.io/basics/todo/</guid>
      <description>Will update soon </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://practice-python.github.io/introduction/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 08:42:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://practice-python.github.io/introduction/overview/</guid>
      <description>Why should I learn Python? Python has been around for nearly 30 years and is still rising in popularity because of some &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; popular usage (Cloud, data science, machine learning&amp;hellip;) and because Python is a really popular first language thanks to his accessibility and quick learning curve.
Remember language is just a tool and your skill will translate to any new language. It&amp;rsquo;s like learning to drive: once you know how to drive, you can drive any car, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t know where the buttons are, you&amp;rsquo;ll always be able to go somewhere with it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>